<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fall 2018 on Sibelius Peng</title><link>https://notes.sibeliusp.com/term/fall-2018/</link><description>Recent content in Fall 2018 on Sibelius Peng</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notes.sibeliusp.com/term/fall-2018/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AMATH 231</title><link>https://notes.sibeliusp.com/amath231/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.sibeliusp.com/amath231/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://notes.sibeliusp.com/crs_banner/calculus_spirit.png" alt="Featured image of post AMATH 231" />&lt;p>&lt;a class="link" href="http://www.math.uwaterloo.ca/~ervrscay" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>ERV&lt;/a> was teaching that. He has &lt;a class="link" href="http://links.uwaterloo.ca/amath231" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>a complete set of notes&lt;/a>. The course is not that hard if you do all assignments. Assignments and exams are similar.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AMATH 251</title><link>https://notes.sibeliusp.com/amath251/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.sibeliusp.com/amath251/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://notes.sibeliusp.com/crs_banner/amath251.png" alt="Featured image of post AMATH 251" />&lt;p>Harsh TA, made the average around 40 for the first 2 assignments deliberately. This is quite different from normal advanced courses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This course is required for AMATH major or minor or joint(?), but you can discuss with advisor if your coop sequence
cannot make this course.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a class="link" href="https://pdf.sibeliusp.com/1189/251.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Here&lt;/a> is a summary.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CO 255</title><link>https://notes.sibeliusp.com/co255old/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.sibeliusp.com/co255old/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://notes.sibeliusp.com/crs_banner/helly.png" alt="Featured image of post CO 255" />&lt;p>&lt;a class="link" href="http://www.math.uwaterloo.ca/~jfgeelen/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Jim Geelen&lt;/a>. Legend. Spent 2~3 lectures on introduction of the course topics and how hard is optimization&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From a review of rate my prof:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Covers so many topics in an intro to CO course as he is such a smart professor. Difficult assignment, better start assignment early and go to his office hour. When I went to higher level CO courses, I realized how great he is. His class is hard, but makes your life easier in future CO courses.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>For example, co 450 students serve the best if they took co 255.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This notes is incomplete.
Check the &lt;a class="link" href="https://notes.sibeliusp.com/co255" >winter 2020 version&lt;/a> for a complete version.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CS 246E</title><link>https://notes.sibeliusp.com/cs246e/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.sibeliusp.com/cs246e/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://notes.sibeliusp.com/crs_banner/vim.png" alt="Featured image of post CS 246E" />&lt;p>This course is pretty much like Lushman&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a class="link" href="https://notes.sibeliusp.com/cs146" >cs 146&lt;/a> style: lots of things, hard, time-consuming, but learn a lot definitely. If you enjoy cs146, definitely consider taking cs246e.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The course is well-structed. It proposes several problems, and solves them to introduce new concepts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>About 50% more contents than &lt;a class="link" href="https://notes.sibeliusp.com/cs246" >cs 246&lt;/a>&amp;hellip; and the final project is VIM (if they didn&amp;rsquo;t change it).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Start the assignments early and go to office hours.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MATH 249</title><link>https://notes.sibeliusp.com/math249/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.sibeliusp.com/math249/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://notes.sibeliusp.com/crs_banner/co.jpg" alt="Featured image of post MATH 249" />&lt;p>He repeated the recurrence example for four times&amp;hellip; spent so much time on calculation, didn&amp;rsquo;t enrich a lot. He did introduced some new topics in enumeration like tilings, but nothing in graph theory, or even less than math 239&amp;hellip; This is more structured with &lt;a class="link" href="http://www.math.uwaterloo.ca/~kpurbhoo/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Kevin&lt;/a>, but much more difficult with assignments and tests, but you have the curve at the end.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The following courses are &lt;a class="link" href="https://notes.sibeliusp.com/co342" >CO 342&lt;/a>/&lt;a class="link" href="https://notes.sibeliusp.com/co442" >442&lt;/a>, CO 330/430.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>STAT 231</title><link>https://notes.sibeliusp.com/stat231/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.sibeliusp.com/stat231/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://notes.sibeliusp.com/crs_banner/stat231.png" alt="Featured image of post STAT 231" />&lt;p>Taught by &lt;a class="link" href="https://mpwallace.github.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Michael Wallace&lt;/a>, who is Biostatistician. He is passionate about what he is teaching and good slides, fair exam (not midterm 2&amp;hellip;). So it would be good to do research with him. His research interest from his website:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>My primary research interest is in causal inference, with a specific focus on dynamic treatment regimes (DTRs) and personalized medicine. Dynamic treatment regimes are sequences of decision rules that take subject-level data (such as age, health status, or prior treatment) as input and recommend actions (such as which drug to take) as output. Working with longitudinal datasets, my work focuses on deriving methodologies that help identify the sequence of treatment decisions that yields the best expected outcome.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>More generally, I&amp;rsquo;m interested in identifying new ways to apply methods from different disciplines in new settings. This includes modifying methodology from one area of statistics so that it may be applied in a different area (such as applying measurement error techniques to dynamic treatment regime problems), or through applying statistical methods to novel problems in the &amp;lsquo;real world&amp;rsquo; of data analysis.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Once I asked him whether he would hire any URA (undergraduate research assistant). Most likely no, because&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>which is not just a matter of grades, but whether their interests/ambitions align closely with my research.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s get back to the course content&amp;hellip; It&amp;rsquo;s more like a broad introduction to statistics with unorganized contents&amp;hellip; It&amp;rsquo;s hard to understand what&amp;rsquo;s going on behind the material because the time doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow that&amp;hellip; So only thing you could do it&amp;rsquo;s to know the formula&amp;hellip; If you are really into these material, consider learning more in your masters.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It teaches you R in R assignments&amp;hellip; which is dumb. Just need to copy the code and run them. Maybe a few definition questions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So be prepared and go to lectures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also you should definitely take stat 241 if possible. Everything should be clear in that course. Wallace is teaching it during winter 2019, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t attend :(&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>